Marcel Breuer Papers
Marcel Breuer Papers
- Project Records, 1922-1982 (inclusive); 1940-1980 (bulk); 89 linear feet of manuscript material, 24,618 drawings, 6,160 photographs and slides.
  - HARNISCHMACHER HOUSE I, Weisbaden, Germany (1932) [Residential, Single]
    - Photographs, 72
      - Breuer in living room chair., finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 118, Folder 5)
      - Living room wall unit and armchair. [dups], finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 2 (Box 118, Folder 6)
      - Study with reclining chair and armchair., finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 118, Folder 6)
      - Study with reclining chair. [dups], finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 4 (Box 118, Folder 6)
      - Armchair from study., finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 118, Folder 6)
      - Work table, wall unit and bookshelves. [dups], finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 2 (Box 118, Folder 6)
      - Pottery display cabinet., finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 118, Folder 6)
      - Dining room. [dups], finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 2 (Box 118, Folder 7)
      - Kitchen., finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 118, Folder 7)
      - Second bedroom., finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 118, Folder 7)
      - Second bedroom table and mirror., finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 118, Folder 7)
      - View of upper terrace from southeastern bedroom., finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 118, Folder 7)
      - Interior stairs to upper level., finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 118, Folder 7)
      - View of Upper Terrace from Above [Roll 3, Frame 6], finished project, exterior view; (negatives) 1 (Box SL-14)
      - View of Upper Terrace from Above [Roll 3, Frame 5], finished project, exterior view; (negatives) 1 (Box SL-14)
      - View of Upper Terrace from Above [Roll 3, Frame 4], finished project, exterior view; (negatives) 1 (Box SL-14)
      - Side Elevation with View of Service Yard [Roll 3, Frame 3], finished project, exterior view; (negatives) 1 (Box SL-14)
      - Side Elevation with View of Service Yard [Roll 3, Frame 2], finished project, exterior view; (negatives) 1 (Box SL-14)
      - View of Upper Terrace from Above [Roll 3, Frame 1], finished project, exterior view; (negatives) 1 (Box SL-14)
      - View of terrace and building façade from ground level. [Slide 362], finished project, exterior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-4)
      - View of house from south terrace. [Slide 123], finished project, exterior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-4)
      - Floor Plan. [Slide 216], drawings, plan; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-4)
      - View of terrace and building façade from ground level. [Slide 591], finished project, exterior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-4)
      - View of lower terrace from living room window with flower arrangement in foreground. [Slide 744], finished project, interior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-4)
      - View of lower terrace from living room window with flower arrangement in foreground. [Slide 426], finished project, interior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-4)
      - View of upper terrace from above. [Slide 215], finished project, exterior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-4)
      - Living room. [dups] [Slide 213], finished project, interior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-4)
      - View of house from terrace. [Slide 214], finished project, exterior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-4)
      - Living room wall unit and armchair (long view). [Slide 354], finished project, interior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-4)
      - Study with reclining chair. [dups] [Slide 584], finished project, interior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-4)
      - Living room wall unit with flower arrangement. [Slide 741], finished project, interior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-4)
      - Living room wall unit and armchair. [dups] [Slide 742], finished project, interior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-4)
  - HARNISCHMACHER HOUSE II, Weisbaden, Germany (1953-1954) [Residential, Single]
    - Drawings, 29
      - Rough sketches., [Design Development Drawings]; (originals) (Box 80, Folder 5)
      - Plans, Framing and Basement Diagrams (1), [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 576)
      - Elevations (2), [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 576)
      - Wall Sections and Details (3), [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 576)
      - Fireplace Details (15 Jun 1954) [original + blueprint], [Working Drawings]; 2; (mixed) (Tube 576)
      - Ventilation Plan (Wilhelm Neuser, May 1954) [in ] [German], [Working Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 576)
      - Perpsective rendering, elevations and plan (7 May 1953)., [Design Development Drawings]; 3; (originals) (Tube 576)
      - Sketches. Perpsective rendering, elevations and plan. Annotated reproductions (16 Jun 1953)., [Design Development Drawings]; 10; (mixed) (Tube 576)
      - Elevations and plan. Reproduction of elevations. (18 Aug 1953)., [Design Development Drawings]; 3; (mixed) (Tube 576)
      - Elevations and plan. Annotated reproduction of elevations (9 Dec 1953)., [Design Development Drawings]; 3; (mixed) (Tube 576)
      - Erdgegeschoss [Mar 1954] [annotated print], [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 576)
      - Garten Harnischmacher: Vogeltranke [12 jan 1954], [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 576)
      - Garten Harnischmacher (Site Plan), [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 576)
      - Misc. Details, [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 576)
    - Project Files
      - Awards (Aug 1955-Dec 1955), Auszeichnung Vorbildlich Gestalteter Neubauten im Weisbaden [German] (Box 80, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence: Associated Architect (Jul 1953-May 1954), Wilhelm Neuser [German] (Box 80, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence: Client (Jan 1953-May 1956), Paul Marianne Harnischmacher [in German and English] (Box 80, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence: Manufacturers (1954), Various Suppliers and Service Providers. Includes invoices. (Box 80, Folder 4)
      - Office Records, Miscellaneous notes and sketches (Box 80, Folder 5)
      - Shop Drawings, Product Literature and Samples, with annotations (Box 80, Folder 6)
      - Transmittals (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Photographs, 11
      - Bird Bath, finished project, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 80, Folder 8)
      - Harnischmacher and House [print], finished project, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 80, Folder 8)
      - Harnischmacher and House [copy negative], finished project, exterior view; (copy negative) 1 (Box 80, Folder 8)
      - Entrance, finished project, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 80, Folder 8)
      - Entrance [Slide 781], finished project, exterior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-14)
      - View of Elevation from Garden with Paul Harnischmacher [Slide 782], finished project, exterior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-14)
      - View of Elevation from Garden with Paul Harnischmacher [Slide 783], finished project, exterior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-14)
      - View of Terrace from Garden [Slide 784], finished project, exterior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-14)
      - View Out from Terrace [Slide 785], finished project, exterior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-14)
      - View Out from Terrace [Slide 786], finished project, exterior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-14)
      - View of Terrace with Paul Harnischmacher [Slide 787], finished project, exterior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-14)
  - HARNISCHMACHER OFFICE, Mainz, Germany (1929) [Interior]
    - Drawings, 8
      - Büro (Nr. 234) [Leaf 206] (Aug 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 8)
      - Büro (Nr. 236) [Leaf 208] (Aug 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 8)
      - Büro (Nr. 238) [Leaf 210] (Aug 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 8)
      - Tisch der Sekretärin (Nr. 240) [Leaf 211] (2 Oct 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 8)
      - Tisch der Sekretärin (Nr. 248) [Leaf 212] (14 Oct 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 8)
      - Büro (Nr. 237) [Leaf 209] (Aug 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 24)
      - Büro (Nr. 233) [Leaf 205] (Aug 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Map-case 75)
      - Büro (Nr. 235) [Leaf 207] (Aug 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Map-case 75)
    - Photographs, 3
      - Small office with desk and cabinets., finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 118, Folder 8)
      - Large office with table and wall units., finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 118, Folder 8)
      - Large office with table and wall units. [Slide 392], finished project, interior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-4)
  - HARVARD UNIVERSITY, BIOLOGY AND CHEMISTRY BUILDING, Cambridge, MA (1969) (not built) [Educational], (Alternate names: Robinson Hall)
    - Drawings, 220
      - Courtyard Perspective. Fine rendering (Larry Perron, n.d.) [graphite on illustration board, 26.25 x 30 in.], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Map-case 118, Folder 8)
      - Detail Perspective. Fine rendering (Larry Perron, n.d.) [graphite on illustration board, 26.25 x 30 in.], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Map-case 118, Folder 9)
      - Large format film negatives for creation of presentation sheets/sets, [Presentation Drawings]; 12; (reproductions) (Tube 1439)
      - Perspective [photostat], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1440)
      - Schematic Design (Oct 1969) (Sheet nos. 1-12 and overlays): Floor Plans, Sections, Elevations, Façade Details, Perspectives, [Presentation Drawings]; 16; (originals) (Tube 1440)
      - Schematic Design (Oct 1969) (Sheet nos. 1-12): Floor Plans, Sections, Elevations, Façade Details, Perspectives, [Presentation Drawings]; 13; (reproductions) (Tube 1440)
      - Site Plans (Nov-Dec 1969), [Design Development Drawings]; 3; (originals) (Tube 1440)
      - Design development drawings (Jul-Aug 1969): includes schematic elevations and panel studies, schematic sections for lecture hall layout, [Design Development Drawings]; 96; (originals) (Tube 1441)
      - Preliminary Schemes (Sep-Oct 1969) (annotated prints), [Design Development Drawings]; 52; (reproductions) (Tube 1443)
      - Existing Building/Conditions [photostats], [Design Development Drawings]; 25; (reproductions) (Tube 1443)
    - Project Files
      - Architect╒s Report (1969) (Box 130, Folder 1)
      - Area Calculations (Box 130, Folder 2)
      - Building codes (1969) (Box 130, Folder 3)
      - Contract (1969) (Box 130, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence: Client (1968-1971), William Gardiner (deputy director, Dept. of Buildings Grounds), Ronald Vanelli (Chemistry dept., building committee co-chair) (Box 130, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence: Suppliers' inquiries with product literature (1969-1970) (Box 130, Folder 6)
      - Financial documents: Cost estimates (1969-1970), John O. Meadows Associates (Box 130, Folder 7)
      - Memoranda (1969-1970), Includes minutes of a 1970 Harvard building committee meeting (Box 130, Folder 8)
      - Transmittal (1969) (Box 130, Folder 9)
    - Published Material
    - Photographs, 16
      - Copies of floor plans from Brookhaven National Lab designs (corridor scheme), drawings, plan; (photocopies) 4 (Box 130, Folder 10)
  - HARVARD YARD PROJECT, Cambridge, MA (1941) (not built) [Educational], (Alternate names: Redesigning Harvard Yard)
    - Published Material
      - Students in Graduate School of Design Plan to Remodel Yard Harvard Crimson (4 Mar 1941), 1 clipping; (newspaper clippings) (Oversize 22, Folder 43)
  - HAUS AM HORN, Weimar, Germany (1922-1923) [Exhibition structures], (Alternate names: Bauhaus exhibition house)
    - Published Material
      - Das Einfamilienwohnhaus des Staatlichen Bauhauses Illustrierte rundschau (1923), 6 pgs.; (Magazine) (Oversize 19, Folder 1)
      - Die Möbelabteilung des Staatlichen Bauhauses zu Weimar Fachblatt für Holtzbeiter (1925), 17-19; (magazine clippings ) (Oversize 19, Folder 4)
      - Die Arbeit des Staatlichen Bauhauses Thuringer Alligemeinen Zeitung (19 Oct 1924), 2 pgs.; (newspaper clippings) (Oversize 19, Folder 25)
    - Photographs, 7
      - Bed. Lemonwood and walnut (Haus-am-Horn)., finished project, detail; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 119, Folder 18)
      - Kitchen., finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 119, Folder 18)
      - Kitchen. [dup of 18:2], finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 119, Folder 18)
      - Bedroom. Axonometric drawing., drawings, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 119, Folder 18)
      - Bedroom. Axonometric drawing. [dup of 18:4], drawings, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 119, Folder 18)
      - Bedroom dressing table. [Slide 672], finished project, interior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-4)
      - Kitchen. [Slide 681], finished project, interior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-4)
  - HAUS M (MELDER HOUSE), Maehrisch-Ostrau, Czechoslovakia (1930) (not built) [Residential, Single], (Alternate names: House in Maehrisch-Ostrau)
    - Drawings, 3
      - Haus m. (Nr. 384) [Leaf 317] (9 Sep 1930), [Presentation Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 4)
      - Haus m.m. (Nr. 384) [Leaf 317a] (9 Sep 1930), [Presentation Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 4)
      - Grundstück Haus m. [Leaf 316], [Design Development Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 25)
    - Project Files
  - HECKSCHER MUSEUM EXPANSION, Huntington, NY (1973-1977) (not built) [Museum]
    - Drawings, 70
      - Heckscher Museum Expansion Project (Sheet Nos. 1-4) [26 Oct 1976] ("work terminated 25 Aug 1977"]: Site Plan, Floor Plans, Elevations, Sections, [Presentation Drawings]; 4; (originals) (Tube 1426)
      - Site Plan [5 Dec 1980], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1426)
      - Preliminary [30 May 1980]: Site Plan, First Floor and Elevations, [Presentation Drawings]; 3; (originals) (Tube 1426)
      - Preliminary Plans [26 Mar 1981]: Site Plan, Basement Plan, First Floor Plan and Elevations ***VERY FRAGILE***, [Presentation Drawings]; 4; (originals) (Tube 1426)
      - Design Development Drawings and Sketches [Dec 1976], [Design Development Drawings]; 26; (originals) (Tube 1426)
      - Preliminary [18 Dec 1973]: Site Plan, Floor Plans, [Presentation Drawings]; 2; (originals) (Tube 1426)
      - Sketch Rendering [n.d.], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1426)
      - Design development SK drawings, unnumbered development drawings,annotated progress prints and draft working drawings [Dec 1976-Aug 1977], [Design Development Drawings]; 22; (mixed) (Tube 1427)
      - Mechanical Plan (SK1-SK3) [10 Aug 1977] (Jansen and Rogen), [Design Development Drawings]; 3; (reproductions) (Tube 1427)
      - Electrical (E1-E2) [Jun 1977], [Design Development Drawings]; 2; (reproductions) (Tube 1427)
      - Egress Diagram (Dwg. Nos. 1-2) [21 Jun 1977], [Design Development Drawings]; 2; (reproductions) (Tube 1427)
  - HEINERSDORFF HOUSE, Berlin, Germany (1929) [Interior]
    - Drawings, 31
      - Ablegeboden in der Anrichte (Nr. 48) [Leaf 38] (9 Jan 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 1)
      - Garderobe Vern. (Nr. 80) [Leaf 69] (28 Feb 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 1)
      - Gartentisch (Nr. 88) [Leaf 74] (8 Mar 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 1)
      - Gemüse Putz Tisch (Nr. 50) [Leaf 40] (9 Jan 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 1)
      - Küchentisch (Nr. 57) [Leaf 46] (14 Jan 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 1)
      - Nachttisch (Nr. 86) [Leaf 72] (6 Mar 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 1)
      - Schrank für Vorräte (Nr. 53) [Leaf 42a] (10 Jan 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 1)
      - Herrenschreibtisch (Nr. 265) [Leaf 222] (25 Nov 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 2)
      - Bildhaken, Vern. (Nr. 79) [Leaf 68] (27 Feb 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 3)
      - Damenzimmer Tisch (Nr. 343) [Leaf 280] (13 Mar 1930), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 3)
      - Umänderung Zeichnung 44 (Nr. 44a) [Leaf 34] (11 Jan 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 3)
      - Bett (Nr. 52) [Leaf 42] (10 Jan 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 6)
      - Bett Herrenzimmer (Nr. 85) [Leaf 71] (6 Mar 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 6)
      - Kamin (Nr. 59) [Leaf 48] (16 Jan 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 6)
      - Kamin (Nr. 59a) [Leaf 49] (25 Jan 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 6)
      - Kaminschrank (Nr. 60) [Leaf 50] (21 Jan 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 6)
      - Nachttisch (Nr. 56) [Leaf 45] (14 Jan 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 6)
      - Wall Cabinet (Nr. 5) [Leaf 4], [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 6)
      - Wall Cabinet (Nr. 6) [Leaf 5] (12 Dec 1928), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 6)
      - Wäscheschrank Eingebaut (Nr. 47) [Leaf 37] (7 Jan 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 6)
      - Kaminshrank (Nr. 66) [Leaf 56] (29 Jan 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 7)
      - Kaminshrank (Nr. 66a) [Leaf 57] (29 Jan 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 7)
      - Schrankwand Herrenzimmer (Nr. 78A) [Leaf 66] (26 Feb 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 7)
      - Schrankwand Herrenzimmer (Nr. 78B) [Leaf 67] (4 Mar 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 7)
      - Schreibtisch (Nr. 54) [Leaf 43] (11 Jan 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 7)
      - Bett (Nr. 252) [Leaf 216] (22 Oct 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 24)
      - Damenzimmer Nachttisch (Nr. 341) [Leaf 278] (8 Mar 1930), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 24)
      - Damenzimmer Toilettentisch (Nr. 342) [Leaf 279] (13 Mar 1930), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 24)
      - Küchenschrank Eingebaut (Nr. 45) [Leaf 35] (7 Jan 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Map-case 75)
      - Wandschrank I (Nr. 43) [Leaf 32] (3 Jan 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Map-case 75)
      - Wandschrank II (Nr. 44) [Leaf 33] (5 Jan 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Map-case 75)
    - Published Material
      - Fireplace Die Pyramide (1929), 1 clipping; (magazine clippings ) (Oversize 19, Folder 15)
    - Photographs, 3
      - Multi-lens window., finished project, detail; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 119, Folder 19)
      - Multi-lens window. [Slide 327], finished project, detail; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-4)
      - Multi-lens window. [Slide 639], finished project, detail; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-4)
  - HERRICK HOUSE, Canajoharie, NY (1949-1950) [Residential, Single]
    - Drawings, 13
      - Property Survey, [Site Surveys]; 1; (originals) (Tube 630)
      - Plot Survey, [Site Surveys]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 630)
      - Plan, 4 Rendered Elevations, Rendered Perspective, [Presentation Drawings]; 2; (originals) (Tube 630)
      - Plans, Sections, Elevations, Details, [Working Drawings]; 6; (originals) (Tube 630)
      - Foundation Plan and Details, [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 630)
      - Heating Plans and Details, [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 630)
      - Revised Piping in Heater Room [29 Nov 1949], [Working Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 630)
    - Project Files
      - Contract, Partial Owner-Contractor Agreement (Box 54, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence: Client I (Mar 1949-Nov 1949), Newton J. Herrick, Jr. and Annette Herrick (Box 54, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence: Client II (Dec 1949-Oct 1952) (Box 54, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence: Consultant (Jun 1949-Nov 1949), Benjamin Spivak (Consulting Engineer), Arthur Sparrow (Civil Engineer) (Box 54, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence: Contractor (Aug 1949-Mar 1950), Raymond Olmstead Construction Co. (Box 54, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence: Manufacturers and Misc. Contractors (1949-50), Suppliers, Misc. Contractors and Service Providers (Box 54, Folder 6)
      - Financial Records I (May 1949-Oct 1952), Architect Invoices (Box 54, Folder 7)
      - Financial Records II, Certificates of Payment (includes Manufacturer and Contractor invoices) (Box 54, Folder 8)
      - Office records, Miscellaneous notes, correspondence, cost summaries and sketches (Box 54, Folder 9)
      - Product Literature (Box 54, Folder 10)
      - Specifications/Schedules, General Specifications, Heating Specifications, Lighting Fixture Sched., Hardware Sched., Plumbing Fixture Specifications (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Photographs, 7
      - Foundation Construction, construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 7 (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - HEYDT APARTMENT, Berlin, Germany (1929) [Interior], (Alternate names: Baron Von der Heydt Apartment)
    - Drawings, 15
      - Eingebauter Schrank Schlafzimmer (Nr. 286) [Leaf 240] (24 Dec 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 2)
      - Gardenrobenschrank (Nr. 282) [Leaf 236] (20 Dec 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 2)
      - Golfhaus (Nr. 278) [Leaf 232] (17 Dec 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 2)
      - Herrenzimmer Chaiselongue (Nr. 281) [Leaf 235] (20 Dec 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 2)
      - Herrenzimmer Heizkörperverkleid (Nr. 293) [Leaf 248] (9 Jan 1930), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 2)
      - Küchenschrank (Nr. 290) [Leaf 244] (24 Dec 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 2)
      - Schrank (Nr. 288) [Leaf 242] (24 Dec 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 2)
      - Zimmer der Sekretärin (Nr. 284) [Leaf 238] (23 Dec 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 2)
      - Bett der Sekretärin (Nr. 285) [Leaf 239] (23 Dec 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 8)
      - Schiebetüren im Herrenzimmer (Nr. 299) [Leaf 254] (24 Jan 1930), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 8)
      - Schnapprollo im Herrenzimmer (Nr. 296) [Leaf 251] (17 Jan 1930), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 8)
      - Bett (Nr. 287) [Leaf 241] (24 Dec 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 24)
      - Chaiselonguebank (Nr. 289) [Leaf 243] (24 Dec 1929), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 24)
      - Herrenzimmer Heizkörperverkl. II (Nr. 294) [Leaf 249] (9 Jan 1930), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 24)
      - Herrenzimmer Schr. (Nr. 283) [Leaf 237] (21 Dec 1929), [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1317)
  - HOOPER HOUSE I, Baltimore, MD (1949) [Residential, Single]
    - Drawings, 26